A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Associates, Fred Smith FA1225
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Associates, Fred Smith
1910-1994, Bulk: 1953-1994
1953-1994
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
Smith, M. Frederik
FA1225
14.12 Cubic Feet 9 legal-size document boxes, 24 letter-size document boxes, 1 half-letter-size document box, and 1 tall legal document box (Boxes 1-35).
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Arrangement
The material in this collection is divided into 14 series: Prudential Insurance Company, Northeastern Home Office; The Vibrane Corporation; Laurance S. Rockefeller – Biography; Laurance S. Rockefeller – Interests and Awards; Fred Smith – Miscellaneous Office Files; United Nations Development Corporation; Vermont Interests; State Park Commission, City of New York; Concessions Reform; Jackson Hole Interests; Hawaiian Civic Projects; Paul Maze Book; Princeton University; and Rockefeller Family. Original folder titles have been primarily maintained.
Biographical / Historical
M. Frederik Smith was born in Fort Wayne, Indiana, on November 24, 1908. He attended the University of Michigan, the College of William and Mary, and the Dayton Art Institute.
Mr. Smith worked in public relations and advertising, served as publicity director for Wendell Willkie's pre-convention presidential campaign in 1940, served as assistant to Treasury Secretary Henry Morgenthau Jr. during World War II, and served as a staff representative of President Franklin D. Roosevelt at the Economic and International Monetary Conference at Bretton Woods, New Hampshire, in 1944. He was a member of the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission (ORRRC) from 1958 to 1962.
As a Senior Vice President of Prudential Insurance Company, Mr. Smith oversaw the building of the company's Northeastern Home Office – the Prudential Center – in Boston. In 1964, he joined Laurance Rockefeller's staff.
At various times, Mr. Smith also was a consultant to the chair of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, a member of the Federal Power Commission's Task Force on Environmental Quality, chair of the State Park Commission for the City of New York, chair of the Staff Executive Committee of the Electric Utility Industry Task Force on Environment, and a panelist at the White House Conference on Natural Beauty.
He served several U.S. presidents, including Harry S. Truman, who appointed Mr. Smith chair of the public relations committee of the National Labor Management Conference; Dwight D. Eisenhower, who named him to the Recreation Resources Review Commission; Lyndon B. Johnson, who appointed him to the Citizens Advisory Committee on Outdoor Recreation and Natural Beauty; and Richard M. Nixon, who appointed him consultant to the Committee on Quality of the Environment.
Mr. Smith retired in 1991. He died on March 12, 1997.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material in this collection represents several accessions of Fred Smith's files made to the Rockefeller Archive Center. The earliest accession, now Series 1 and 2, is undated and contains material that predates Fred Smith's employment with Laurance Rockefeller. The material in Series 3 through 14 was received in three separate accessions during 1998 and dates from the years of Mr. Smith's tenure as an associate of Mr. Rockefeller.
Scope and Contents
Fred Smith's interest in conservation, outdoor recreation, and the environment predate his association with Laurance Rockefeller. Yet because of this interest and Mr. Smith's talent in public relations and politics, he often acted as Mr. Rockefeller's representative, and his involvement in numerous commissions, committees, conferences, and organizations is documented throughout these files.
The files also give an overview of the breadth of Laurance Rockefeller's conservation interests, stretching from Vermont in the northeast (Series 7) to Jackson Hole, Wyoming, (Series 10), and continuing west to Hawaii (Series 11).
- Prudential Insurance Company, Northeastern Home Office, 1956-1964; 1; 3.77 Cubic Feet 8 legal document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1 contains extensive information on the building of the Prudential Insurance Company's Northeastern Home Office in Boston, Massachusetts, during the early 1960's. Mr. Smith, as a Senior Vice President of the Prudential, was directly involved in the insurance company's negotiations with the city of Boston, the Turnpike Authority, the Metropolitan Transit Authority, and others. These files give a glimpse into the political scene in Boston at the time as well as containing facts and figures related to the actual construction.
  - Boston, 1956 June-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Boston: Northeastern Home Office, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2-5, Box 2, Folder 6-11, Box 3, Folder 12-14, 16, 19-20, Box 4, Folder 22, 24-27, 29, 31)
    General
    Date ranges for individual folders: 2 (January-February 1957); 3 (March-August 1957); 4 (September-December 1957); 5 (January-February 1958); 6 (March-June 1958); 7 (July-September 1958); 8 (October-December 1958); 9 (January-March 1959); 10 (April-June 1959); 11 (July-December 1959); 12 (January-April 1960); 13 (May 1960); 14 (June-July 1960); 16 (August 1960); 19 (September-October 1960); 20 (November-December 1960); 22 (January-March 1961); 24 (April-May 1961); 25 (June-September 1961); 26 (October-December 1961); 27 (January-March 1962); 29 (April-December 1962); 31 (January 1963-April 1964)
  - Boston Press Conference: Regional Impact of Prudential Home Office on City and Area, 1960 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Boston: Redevelopment Plan, 1960 September (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Boston: Official City Directory, 1960 September (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Final Drafts, 1960 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fred Smith Report to Board, 1961 February 14 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Savings Banks, 1957-1962 January (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Boston: Northeastern Home Office, 1962 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 29A)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Closed material: Application for Federal Employment
  - Institute of Contemporary Art, 1962 June (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Boston: Apartment Houses, 1958-1960, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - City Taxes, 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - City Taxes: Tax Exempt Property Figures and Land, Building Valuations, 1958, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Boston: Executive Committee Minutes, 1956-1957, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Boston: Historic Sites, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Convention Hall, 1957-1962 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Suggested Sites - Prudential Projects: New England Area Location: General Correspondence: Miscellaneous Letters Referred to Mr. Smith, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Boston, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Conference on Municipal Administration, Boston: Panel Presentation - "Old Problems - New Approaches", by Fred Smith, 1958 November (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Prudential Center, Boston: Fact Sheet, 1958, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Mechanics Hall Demolition, Boston, 1959 January 8 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Boston: Prudential Center: Estimated Costs, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Site Market Analysis - Back Bay Yards, Boston, Massachusetts: Prepared for Prudential Insurance Company by Real Estate Research Corporation, 1956 October 18 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Boston: Hotel, 1956-1959, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Metropolitan Transit Authority, 1957 February, 1959 March (Box 6, Folder 46-47)
    Folder 46: Report Regarding Transit Operation on the Newton Highlands Branch of the Boston and Albany Railroad; Folder 47: Report Regarding Proposed Subway Facilities Required to Meet Additional Loads from The Prudential and Government Center Projects
  - Proposal for the Construction of Prudential Center, Boston, Massachusetts: Submitted by Perini-Volpe-Raymond-Walsh, 1957 June (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Deeds, Contracts and Other Material Bearing on the Construction of the Boston Project, with Explanatory Memorandum, Harry B. Hyde, 1957 July 24 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Boston: Massachusetts Turnpike Authority, 1957, 1959-1960, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Boston: Prudential Center: Tax Plan, 1958, 1960, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Massachusetts Senate and House Bills, 1960-1961, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Extra Clippings and Miscellaneous Boston, 1956-1959 (Box 7, Folder 53-54)
    Folder 53 (1956-1957); Folder 54 (1958-1959)
  - Prudential Center, Boston, Massachusetts: Plaza-Subterranean East Section: A. Possible Ultimate Plan; B. Present Plan: Maps and Photos, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Boston: Architect and Engineers Memos (including Pereira and Luckman), 1956-1962 (Box 7, Folder 56-59, Box 8, Folder 60-62)
    Folder 56 (1956 August-1957 July); Folder 57 (1957 August-December); Folder 58 (1958 January-March); Folder 59 (1958 April-December); Folder 60 (1959 January-December); Folder 61 (1960 January-December); Folder 62 (1961 January-1962 May)
- The Vibrane Corporation, 1953-1962; 2; 0.94 Cubic Feet 2 legal document boxes
  Series 2 documents the brief history of The Vibrane Corporation. The Corporation's Shareholders Agreement, dated January 8, 1953, lists Michael Wibault and Winthrop Rockefeller as shareholders. Wibault's part was to engage in research and development of inventions relating to methods of propulsion and Winthrop Rockefeller's part was to furnish funds for such research and development to continue. The Corporation was dissolved in 1962.
  - Certificate of Incorporation and By-Laws, 1953 January (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Minutes, 1953-1962 (Box 8, Folder 64-65)
    Folder 64 (1953-1956); Folder 65 (1957-1962)
  - Certificate of Dissolution, 1962 March (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Salary and Employment Records, 1953-1962 (Box 8, Folder 66A)
    Closed material: Salary and employment records
  - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Second Progress Report - Vibrane Pump, 1954 April (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Final Report - Vibrane Pump, 1955 March (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - University of Arkansas: Vibrane Corporation Project: Salaries and Expenditures, 1954 January-March (Box 8, Folder 69A)
    Closed material: Salaries and Expenditures
  - Report on the Wibault Ground Attack Gyropter, 1956 June (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Audit of Accounts and Financial Records (Box 9, Folder 71-73)
    Folder 71 (1953 December-1956 December); Folder 72 (1957 December-1959 December); Folder 73 (1960 December-1961 December)
- Laurance S. Rockefeller - Biography, 1915-1988; 3; 1.99 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes and 1 legal box
  Series 3 contains information for a proposed biography of Laurance Rockefeller, including copies of letters and telegrams between Mr. Rockefeller and his parents during his school years (ages 10-23). Drafts of Mr. Smith's own unpublished biography of Mr. Rockefeller, variously titled "Notes on the Life and Times of John D. Rockefeller's 3rd Grandson" and "The Third Grandson", are included.
  - Spelman Genealogy: The English Ancestry and American Descendants of Richard Spelman of Middletown, Connecticut, 1700, by Fannie Cooley Williams Barbour, 1910 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    Bound Volume, Copyright 1910, and dedicated by the author to her cousin, Laura Spelman Rockefeller
  - Correspondence Between Laurance S. Rockefeller and His Parents, 1915-1947 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Letters and Telegrams from John D. Rockefeller Jr. to Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1920-1933 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Letters and Telegrams from Abby Aldrich Rockefeller to Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1920-1933 (Box 10, Folder 77-78)
  - Biography: Hotchkiss and Yellin, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Interview with Ed Edwin, 1976 January 10 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Interview with Hugh Morrow (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Interview with Yellin and Hotchkiss, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 82-83)
  - The LSR Book, Draft, 1981 August 25 (Box 11, Folder 84, Box 12, Folder 85)
    Folder 84 - Preface, Books I-III; Folder 85 - Books IV-VI
  - Notes on the Life and Times of John D. Rockefeller's 3rd Grandson, Compiled by his long-time Associate M. Frederik Smith (Box 12, Folder 86)
  - "The Third Grandson", Working Copy (Box 13, Folder 87-88)
    Folder 87 - Volume 1; Folder 88 - Volume 2
  - Material for Archives, 1926-1988 (Box 13, Folder 89)
- Laurance S. Rockefeller - Interests and Awards, 1965-1992; 4; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - White House Conference on Natural Beauty: Press Coverage, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 90-91, Box 14, Folder 92)
  - Charles Evans Hughes Award 1972, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 93)
  - Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center: Award to Laurance S. Rockefeller "for Outstanding Support of Biomedical Science", 1982 May 17 (Box 14, Folder 94)
  - Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center: Ground Breaking Ceremony: Rockefeller Research Laboratories, 1986 June 24 (Box 14, Folder 95)
  - The Fund for the Enhancement of the Human Spirit: Meeting of February 21, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 96)
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller: On His 80th Birthday, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 97)
  - Congressional Gold Medal Presentation to Laurance S. Rockefeller: Acknowledgement and Appreciation by Members and Trustees of Jackson Hole Preserve and American Conservation Association, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 98)
  - Foreign Policy Association Photo Album Presented to Mary French Rockefeller and Laurance S. Rockefeller (Box 14, Folder 99)
  - "National Parks for the 21st Century" - The Vail Agenda - from the Steering Committee of the 75th Anniversary Symposium, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 100)
- Fred Smith - Miscellaneous Office Files, 1942-1996; 5; 2.66 Cubic Feet 7 letter document boxes
  - Adirondack and Catskill Parks, 1967, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 101)
  - Adirondack Forest Preserve: Maps, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 102)
  - Horace Albright, 1964, 1966-1969, 1976-1981 (Box 15, Folder 103)
  - Archives, 1974, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 104)
  - Banneker School: "The True Meaning of Christmas", Ray Frances Scott, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 105)
    - "The True Meaning of Christmas" - The Banneker School, 2017:FA1225:001 (Box 15, Folder 105)
      Magnetic tape. Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an archivist for further details.
  - Bethesda Academy of Performing Arts: Lucy Waletzky, 1984-1986 (Box 15, Folder 106)
  - "C" General Correspondence, 1975-1979, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 107)
  - Career with Zoo, 1935 to End (Retirement), 1987, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 108)
  - Central Hudson Gas and Electric Company, 1965-1967, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 109)
  - Citizens Committee for the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission Report (CORC), 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 110)
  - "The Complete Sayings of Jesus", Introduction by Harry Emerson Fosdick, Copyright 1942 (Box 15, Folder 111)
  - The Conservation Foundation, 1949-1971 (Box 16, Folder 112-117)
    Folder 113 - "The Conservation Foundation: A Statement of Purpose and the Proposed Program for 1948"; Folder 114 - "The Conservation Foundation: A Description of its Purposes..."; Folder 115 - Annual Reports 1949-1953; Folder 116 - Annual Reports 1954-1957, 1960; Folder 117 - Annual Reports 1961-1964, 1970-1971
  - Consolidated Edison, 1964-1975, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 118, Box 17, Folder 119)
    Folder 118 - 1964-1966; Folder 119 - 1967-1975, 1977
  - Calvin Coolidge Memorial Foundation: "Grace Coolidge and Her Era" by Ishbel Ross, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 120)
    Foreword by Mary French Rockefeller
  - Council of Parks and Forest Reserve, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 121, 123)
    Folder 121 - Book I; Folder 123 - Book II
  - The Forest Preserve and the Renaissance of the Hudson River - A Report (Box 17, Folder 122)
  - Council on Environmental Quality, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 124)
  - Dana Creel: Rockefeller Brothers Fund: Man and His Urban Environment, 1971-1972, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 125)
  - "D" General Correspondence, 1965, 1971-1973, 1975-1979, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 126)
  - General Electric FORUM, Volume VIII, Number 4, October-December 1965: "A New Sense of Urgency" by Laurance S. Rockefeller (Box 18, Folder 127)
  - Holism, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 128)
  - Louis O. Kelso, 1968-1970, 1974, 1976-1977, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 129)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, 1964-1969, 1971-1973, 1976-1978 (Box 18, Folder 130)
  - "L" General Correspondence, 1967-1969, 1971-1977, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 131)
  - Land and Water Bill, 1963-1964, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 132)
  - "The Lincheng Incident: How One Thousand Bandits Changed International Politics" by Molly Fitzgibbon Whalen, 1996 April 15 (Box 18, Folder 133)
  - Liquid Waste, 1969-1971 (Box 18, Folder 134)
  - Little Stony Point, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 135)
  - Long Island State Park Commission, 1964-1967 (Box 18, Folder 136)
  - "Man and His Urban Environment" Project, 1972-1978, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 137-138)
    Folder 138 - Clippings
  - F. E. Masland Jr., 1966-1975, 1979-1981 (Box 19, Folder 139)
  - "Flora Whitney Miller: Her Life, Her World", Whitney Museum of Art, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 140)
  - Mitre Corporation, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 141)
  - F. S. Moseley and Co., 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 142)
  - National Cancer Advisory Board, 1972, 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 143)
  - National Park Service, 1983-1984, 1986, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 144-145)
    Folder 145 - "The First 75 Years"
  - National Park System Advisory Board, 1983-1985 (Box 20, Folder 146)
  - New York State Historic Trust, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 147)
  - New York State Recreation Council Advisory Committee, 1964-1967 (Box 20, Folder 148)
  - Donal O'Brien, 1968, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 149)
  - Ella Raines Book, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 150)
  - Save-the-Redwoods League, 1964-1966 (Box 20, Folder 151)
  - South Street Seaport Museum, 1968-1970 (Box 20, Folder 152)
  - University of Wyoming: Conservation History and Research Center: Fred Smith Collection, 1972-1981, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 153)
  - Valley Ranch, Cody, Wyoming: Assessment of the Development Potential, 1986 September (Box 21, Folder 154)
  - White House Conference on Natural Beauty, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 155)
  - Robin Winks, 1980-1986, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 156-159)
    Folder 157 - "George Perkins Marsh, Frederick Billings and the Vermont Tradition", A Report Submitted to the Woodstock Foundation; Folder 158 - Contract: Frederick Billings Biography; Folder 159 - Frederick Billings Biography: An Overview of the Book
- United Nations Development Corporation, 1964-1981; 6; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - United Nations Development Corporation, 1964-1981 (Box 21, Folder 160, Box 22, Folder 161-165)
    Folder 160 - 1964-1965; Folder 161 - 1966-1967; Folder 162 - 1969 January-August; Folder 163 - 1969 October-December; Folder 164 - 1970-1972; Folder 165 - 1973-1974, 1977, 1980-1981
- Vermont Interests, 1967-1990; 7; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - The Ottauquechee Project, 1967-1973, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 166-167)
    Folder 166 - 1967-1969; Folder 167 - 1970-1973, 1978
  - Woodstock Conservancy Center: Content Summary and Final Design Concept, 1980 June 28 (Box 23, Folder 168)
  - "Commemorative Album: America's First Ski Tow", Woodstock, Vermont, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 169)
  - "The Legacy of Bessie Dashiell", Copyright: The Woodstock Foundation, 1978, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 170-171)
    Folder 171 - Possible New Edition
  - "Townscape: Woodstock", Vermont Magazine, Volume 2, Number 1, 1990 January/February (Box 23, Folder 172)
- State Park Commission, City of New York, 1966-1972; 8; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  - State Park Commission for the City of New York, 1969-1972 (Box 23, Folder 173-174)
    Folder 173 - #1-44 (1970-1972); Folder 174 - #45-74 (1969)
  - State Park Commission for the City of New York, Harlem River State Park, 1966-1968 (Box 23, Folder 175)
    Folder 175 - #76-111
  - State Park Commission for the City of New York, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 176-177)
    Folder 176 - #112-149; Folder 177 - #150-184
  - State Park Commission for New York City, Harlem River State Park, 1969-1972 (Box 24, Folder 178-180)
    Folder 178 - #184-207; Folder 179 - #208-230; Folder 180 - Miscellaneous #231-236
  - State Park Commission of New York City, Riverbank Park (Box 25, Folder 181-183)
    Folder 181 - #237-250; Folder 182 - #251-269; Folder 183 - Miscellaneous Information #270-272
- Concessions Reform, 9; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - National Park Concessions Reform I - 1974-1978 and "Preface" (#1a-20) (Box 25, Folder 184)
  - Public Benefit Corporation I - Hearing to Draft Bill - April-December 1979 (#21-39) (Box 25, Folder 185)
  - Public Benefit Corporation II - Negotiations - 1980 (#40-77) (Box 25, Folder 186)
  - Public Benefit Corporation - 1981 (#78-114) (Box 26, Folder 187)
- Jackson Hole Interests, 1955-1990; 10; 2.1 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes and 1 legal document box
  - "Jackson Lake Lodge Dedication", Source: "Planning and Civic Comment", 1955 September (Box 26, Folder 188)
  - Interview with Richard Winger, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 189)
    - Interview with Richard Winger, 1957; 2017:FA1225:002 (Box 26, Folder 189)
      Cassette tape. Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an archivist for further details.
  - The Jackson Hole Preserve Project: Oral History Research Project, Columbia University: Horace M. Albright, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 190-191)
    Folder 190 - pp. 1-119; Folder 191 - pp. 120-240
  - The Jackson Hole Preserve Project, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University: Harry E. Klissold, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 192)
  - The Jackson Hole Preserve Project, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University: Ed Edwin Conversations with Jack Dornan and Mr. and Mrs. Fabian, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 193)
  - The Jackson Hole Preserve Project, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University: Homer C. Richards, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 194)
  - The Jackson Airport 1973-1982 (Box 26, Folder 195, Box 27, Folder 196-199, Box 28, Folder 200-201)
    Folder 195 - I. Raytheon Program to First Jackson Hole Preserve, Incorporated Trustees Action (Items 1-19); Folder 196 - II. Investigation of South Park to Driggs - 1974-1975 (Items 20-70); Folder 197 - III. Further Studies - 1976-1978 (Items 71-108); Folder 198 - IV. Daniel Site - 1979-1980 (Items 109-139); Folder 199 - IV. Daniel Site - 1979-1980 (Items 140-174); Folder 200 - XFAA - Transportation: Negotiations - 1980-1982 - Book I (Items 175-211); Folder 201 - XFAA - Transportation: Negotiations - 1980-1982 - Book II (Items 212-226)
  - Jackson Airport Effort, 1982-1983 (Box 28, Folder 202-204)
    Folder 202 - Book I: Sequence of Events since November 1980; Folder 203 - Book II: Requested Speas Material; Folder 204 - Book III: Basic Conclusions and Pertinent Responses
  - "Why the Jackson Airport Needs to be Replaced: A New Report with New Data" [ACCESS COPY] (Box 28, Folder 205)
  - "Why the Jackson Airport Needs to be Replaced: A New Report with New Data" [RESTRICTED DUE TO PRESERVATION CONCERNS] (Box 35, Folder 253)
    Closed material due to preservation concerns. An access copy of this entire Report is available; LSR papers, Associates, Fred Smith, Box 28, Folder 205
  - Preliminary Airport Layout Plan, Webb Draw Airport, to Serve Jackson, Wyoming (Box 29, Folder 206)
  - Airport, 1980-1982 (Box 29, Folder 207)
  - Webb Draw Airport Research and Planning, Reference Materials, as of November 18, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 208)
  - Jackson Hole Airport: Sierra Club, Wyoming Chapter, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 209)
  - Paste-ups re Airport/Park History (Box 29, Folder 210)
- Hawaiian Civic Projects, 1974-1979; 11; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes